Jordan Kelly

(415) 319-4676 | jordan.j.kelly12@gmail.com | Sacramento, CA

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/the-real-jordan-kelly | GitHub: github.com/profjjk

Portfolio: https://jordankelly.netlify.app/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full-stack software developer specializing in JavaScript and Java. Leveraging an advanced degree in psychology and a diverse professional background to build web applications focused on excellent user experience. Graduate of two coding bootcamps from U.C. Berkeley and Southern Methodist University.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Front End: JavaScript, React.js, React Native, Redux, React Query, JQuery, Handlebars, Bootstrap
- Back End: Java, Node.js, Express, Spring Boot Framework, JUnit, Jest
- Database: MySQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, Mongoose
- Basics: Git, GitHub, HTML5, CSS3, SCSS/Sass
- Deployment: AWS, Heroku, Firebase, Netlify
- Knowledge: OOP, RESTful APIs, MVC Structure, Microservice Architecture, Test Driven Development

Featured Projects

Metronics, Inc., CRM Web Application | Live Demo | GitHub Link

- A customized tool to digitize the company's methods for organizing and tracking customers and service requests, and assist with inventory management.
- Built using the MERN stack (MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js) with JWT authentication and app-wide state management via React Query.
- Java version of this application utilizing the Spring framework and a microservice architecture can be viewed at github.com/profijk/metronics-microservice-build.

Metronics, Inc., Official Website | Website Link | GitHub Link

- The company's first-ever website where customers can learn about the company, submit online requests for service, and browse equipment for sale.
- Built using JavaScript, Node.js, Express.js, JQuery, SCSS/Sass, MongoDB/Mongoose, rendered using the Handlebars templating engine, and deployed on AWS.

UnderOneRoof, Web Application | <u>Live Demo</u> | <u>GitHub Link</u>

- A household management tool for roommates to delegate chores, manage a household budget and track shared expenses, notify each other of relevant events, and look up emergency contact info.
- Built using Node.js, Express.js, React.js, MySQL/Sequelize, Bootstrap for styling, JWT authentication and app-wide state management via Redux. Deployed on Heroku and Netlify.

Professional Experience

Software Developer | Metronics, Inc | Contract

7/2021 - Present

Designed, developed, and deployed the company's first website and a CRM web application for office use.

- Shifting customer interactions from the telephone to an online platform has significantly improved customer satisfaction, reduced errors in scheduling, and increased equipment sales by over 20%.
- The CRM application allows office personnel to find customers and invoices much faster by searching a digital database, and it has prevented service delays by improving inventory supply management.

Field Technician | Metronics, Inc | Contract

4/2016 - 12/2020

Trained mechanics and serviced heavy equipment for auto repair shops.

Financial Advisor | Edward Jones Investments | Full-time

8/2014 - 4/2016

Managed investment and retirement portfolios for individuals and small businesses.

Assistant Manager | Umpqua Bank | Full-time

2/2013 - 8/2014

Trained new employees for the branch and oversaw its operational compliance.

English Teacher | Jiangsu University of Technology, China | Contract

9/2009 - 6/2012

Developed and implemented an English language learning curriculum for undergraduates.

Education

Java & React Native Certificate	Southern Methodist University, TX	5/2021 - 7/2021
Full Stack Web Development Certificate	University of California, Berkeley	12/2020 - 3/2021
Psychology, M.A.	Sonoma State University, CA	8/2007 - 7/2011
Psychology, B.A.	University of Nevada, Reno	8/2002 - 7/2007

Jordan Kelly - Curriculum Vitae